JACK BIS



Experienced in brand management & development, PR, content marketing, email marketing, social media marketing & advertising, analytics, digital & traditional advertising, and event production. I relish the challenge of analysing data, developing a strategy to suit, and then implementing a full channel marketing solution to achieve a desired outcome, all whilst telling a hell of a great story along the way! Professional, with a proud sense of humour, I pride myself on my ability to solve problems and come up with creative solutions. From assisting Premier League clubs with sponsorship strategies, and developing in-stadia WiFi and fan engagement solutions in Europe, to building major event brands and growing Spartan in Australia and New Zealand, my experience has provided me with a unique skill set. In short, I love a good challenge and working with great people to solve problems and generate growth.



EXPERIENCE



MARKETING & MEDIA MANAGER

Aug 2017 - Aug 2019 (2 years)



Melbourne, Australia

INSPIRE

MARKETING & MEDIA MANAGER (Contract)

Oct 2017 - Aug 2019 (1 year, 10 months)



Melbourne, Australia



MARKETING SPECIALIST

Mar 2017 - Aug 2017 (6 months)



Melbourne, Australia



INSIGHT & MARKETING EXECUTIVE

Aug 2015 - Sep 2016 (1 year, 2 months)



London, UK

FLIGHT CENTRE

INTERNATIONAL TRAVEL CONSULTANT

Feb 2015 - Aug 2015 (7 months)



London, UK

STRENGTHS

Logical Problem Solver

Time & People Manager

Relationship Builder

Team Leader

Analytical

Works Well Under Pressure

Creative

AREAS OF EXPERTISE

- ◆ Brand Management & Development
- Social Media, Content, Email, & Digital Marketing
- PPC Advertising & SEO
- Traditional Media Advertising Campaigns
- ◆ Skilled in WordPress, Photoshop, Salesforce & Zoho CRM, Social Media & Email Marketing Tools, Microsoft Office Suite, Google Analytics & Tag Manager, with working knowledge of HTML & CSS
- ♦ Development of Digital Solutions (Websites, Landing Pages, Mobile Apps, Integrated CRM Solutions)
- ◆ Public Relations & Management of Media
- ♦ Marketing Campaign & Project Management
- ♦ Event Production & Management
- ♦ Monetisation of Sports Team Assets
- ♦ Evaluation & Analysis of Sports Sponsorship
- ♦ HD Wi-Fi & Mobile App Development & Analytics

EDUCATION



UNIVERSITY OF OTAGO

Bachelor of Commerce Marketing Major, Psychology Minor

Jan 2012- Dec 2014



MASS PARTICIPATION EVENT BRAND

MARKETING & MEDIA MANAGER

My most recent role saw me responsible for all Marketing & Media functions across the business. From developing our brand strategy and key messaging, producing creative and video content, and managing a small team, to implementing traditional and digital advertising strategies, managing media, and building the major event that is Spartan, no day was the same.

Highlights include:

- Awarded Spartan's Best International Marketing Campaign in 2018 (out of 40 countries)
- Increasing event registrations by over 49% YOY
- Lowering our CPA from an average of \$14 to \$6
- Developing and implementing a social media strategy that increased Facebook following by 32% and Instagram following by 66%
- Introduction of a content strategy that has resulted in an average organic Facebook reach of 4.4 million per week



STRATEGY & EVENT CONSULTANCY

MARKETING & MEDIA MANAGER (CONTRACT)

My contract role saw me responsible for all Marketing & Media functions across the business. With the help of a small but powerful team, I've assisted with the development of two major event brands from scratch in partnership with a state level government.

This involved:

- Building and managing two separate brand strategies
- Designing and assisting with the build of two websites
- Management of marketing budget
- Managing and briefing external contractors including graphic designers, video production team, web design team and a public relations team
- Developing and implementing a full scale marketing plan across both traditional (Radio, TV, Print) and digital channels (Google Ads, Facebook advertising, social media)



SPORTS TRAVEL CONSULTANCY

MARKETING SPECIALIST

My role was varied but primarily focused on digital and social marketing, and content development.

This involved:

- The development of a social media strategy to fit in line with Sportsnets' strategic objectives, grow brand awareness, and increase website traffic
- Development of EDM campaigns
- Day to day management of Twitter, Facebook, & Instagram platforms.
- Day to day management of paid Facebook (Lead Gen, Click, & Traffic campaigns) and Google AdWords advertising spend
- The development and analytics of the Sportsnet website through the use of Google Analytics,
 Wordpress etc.
- The creation & management of a content section on the website dubbed "Fanzone". I also created and managed blog articles, photos, and videos for the FanZone



SPORTS MARKETING AGENCY

INSIGHT & MARKETING EXECUTIVE

My role involved:

- Tech project management & day to day contact with key clients and suppliers
- Being part of a team that developed, managed and reported on the award winning Celtic LIVE matchday
 app
- Reporting to key clients, and analysis of the Award winning Stadium Live HD WiFi solution at Celtic Park
- Undertaking asset evaluations and making recommendations to Premier League, Football League and Rugby clubs to aid them in realising their full commercial potential
- Conducting bi annual sponsorship evaluations for a multi national, blue chip financial brand
- Social media content creation, management, reporting and analysis
- Website content creation, management, reporting and analysis (WordPress)
- Blog planning and creation
- The provision of insights & sales material to UK based sales teams to assist in the sale of In-Stadia media (Giant screens, LED, Concourse TV, Posters)
- Advanced use of Microsoft Office suite. Excel in particular